Guide to the Margaret Paton Diaries, 1849-1872
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
Margaret Paton Diaries 1849-1872
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University
Paton, Margaret, b. 1831.
0.5 Linear Feet 16 Items
Paton was the wife of a merchant from Montrose, Scotland.
The collection includes sixteen diaries written by Paton between 1849-1872.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Margaret Paton Diaries were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a purchase in 1990.
Biographical Note
Margaret Paton was the wife of a merchant from Montrose, Scotland.
Collection Overview
The collection includes sixteen diaries (1849 Oct. 1 to 1872 Dec. 31) kept by Margaret Paton, beginning seven months after her marriage and continuing with little interruption for twenty-three years. She chiefly records her thoughts and moods, how she spends her days, and various events such as the marriages and deaths of persons she knows. Many entries include information about her husband's activities and to a lesser degree her relationship with him. While sometimes recording events of national significance, she primarily focuses on private life and events at a local level.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Paton, Thomas Bell
Diaries -- Women authors
Domestic relations -- Scotland
Families -- Scotland
Marriage -- Scotland
Women -- Family relationships
Merchants -- Scotland
Scotland -- Social life and customs -- 19th century
Montrose (Scotland)--History -- 19th century
Scotland -- Commerce
Scotland -- History -- 19th century
Diaries
Contents of Collection
- Container List, 1849-1872, (1 box)
  - Diary, 1849-1850 (Box 1)
  - Diary, 1851
  - Diary, 1852
  - Diary, 1853
  - Diary, 1854-1856
  - Diary, 1857-1858
  - Diary, 1858-1859
  - Diary, 1859-1860
  - Diary, 1860-1862
  - Diary, 1863-1864
  - Diary, 1865
  - Diary, 1866
  - Diary, 1867
  - Diary, 1868
  - Diary, 1869-1870
  - Diary, 1871-1872